Dmitry Pershin

☑ dapper1291@gmail.com www.linkedin.com/in/dapper91

✓ Yekaterinburg, Russian Federation **1** dapper 91. github.io

Software engineer with more than six years of experience working on projects from different fields like cybersecurity, decentralized apps, cloud computing, distributed systems, fintech; looking to become a part of an experienced developer team to work on creating innovative software and services.

Education

Ural State Technical University, M.S.in computer science, faculty of radio engineering, summa cum laude

Experience

Software Engineer at Tochka Bank / 05.2019 - present

- Designed, developed and launched the quick payments service. It had been implemented from scratch and handled hundreds of thousands of payments a day. The service became profitable in one year after the launch. Quick payments service is a financial infrastructure that provides an ability to make payments without cash or plastic cards using a QR-code (merchant side) and a mobile phone app (customer side) in near-real-time.
- Fully designed, implemented and configured CI/CD process including unit and integration testing, code analysis, application build and deployment which increased code quality, lowered bugs quantity and reduced feature release delay to several minutes.
- Took part in development of financial analysis web tools backend that helped entrepreneurs to possess comprehensive information about theirs financial statistics. The tools provided a lot of visual information like charts and tables based on statistical analysis, classification and clusterization algorithms that helped out customers to reduce their expenses. As a result the service received positive user feedback and most of the customers extended theirs trial subscription.

Software Engineer at Yandex / 11.2018 - 05.2019

- Took part in development of a highly-performant and highly-available task scheduler SAAS that provided optimal company cluster resources utilization which reduced the company expenses more than 10%. The service was able to store and process several petabytes of user data in multiple data centers.
- Took part in development and improvement of service API and SDK providing an ability to describe complex execution pipelines on several thousand of servers in multiple data centers. As a result the service was able to provide availability 99.99%.

Software Engineer at USSC Ltd. / 08.2016 - 11.2018

- Took part in development of software for industrial networks cybersecurity analysis, malware attacks prevention and network traffic inspection. The product was able to detect cyberattacks on enterprise networks and helped in incident investigation at critical facilities.
- Rewritten some security modules from multi-threaded to asynchronous execution model which **increased soft-ware performance more than 50%** and made it possible to monitor much more production facilities without hardware update.
- Developed a module that used SCAP (security content automation protocol) standard to analyze OS integrity and protection using open world-wide vulnerability database which let the system to detect 0-day vulnerabilities as soon as possible.

Skills

Languages	Databases	Frameworks/Libs	VCS	Other	
Rust	PostgreSQL	tokio	Git	Linux	Distributed Systems
Python	MongoDB	asyncio		Docker	Machine Learning Basics
C/C++	Redis	aiohttp		Kubernetes	Networking
	Elasticsearch	flask		RabbitMQ	SQL
		scikit-learn		Kafka	CI/CD
					BASH